Email: stevenchris240@gmail.com https://github.com/Steven-Chris Mobile: +91-7994599928

#### ABOUT ME

I am a software developer that enjoys creating software that in some way benefits people. My greatest strength is my aptitude for quick learning, which aids in my desire to study cutting-edge technologies that are pertinent to my line of work. I enjoy finding solutions to issues that can improve the user experience. In my spare time, I engage as an artist.

### RESUME SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with 1+ years of hands-on experience designing, developing, and implementing applications and solutions, and setting up the deployment environment and CI/CD pipeline and other necessary infrastructure using a range of technologies and programming languages. Seeking to leverage broad development experience and hands-on technical expertise in a challenging role as a Full-stack Developer DevOps Engineer.

#### EDUCATION

### S. R.B. S. Gujarati college

Bachelors in Computer Applications

Cochin, Kerala July. 2018 - July. 2021

#### EXPERIENCE

## Spexmojo Technologies

Software Engineer - Node.JS

Mathikere, Bangalore April 2022 - present

- o GJ App: GJ is a B2B platform that helps optics retailers to easily work with thier lens manufacturer, GKB. My responsibilities were to design and Develop new APIs as well as Maintain the legacy code. I. was also responsible for the DevOps side of things.
- Spexmojo: Spexmojo is a platform that helps consumers to find quality spectacles and match them with a partner store all in a seamless experience.
- o GJ Lite: GJ Lite is a platform similar to GJ but it comes with limited access to various features. This is used by employees under the store owner.

### Hashtag Systems

Infopark, Cochin

Software Engineer

December 2021 - Feb 2022

o Travel Buddy: Travel Buddy is an online social media platform that brings together tourists with similar likes. Users can plan their own journeys or join existing ones created by other users. My responsibilities were to design and Develop new APIs and also manual deployment to AWS.

### Coderight Technologeis

Whitefield, Bangalore

Software Developer

August 2021 and November 2021

- Company Website: Lead the development of the company website from planning to production. Made the website completely modular, making it extremely easy to add, remove or edit the pages of the website.
- EME Construction Roofing Company: EME providing services for all roofing needs from new roofs, extensions, guttering, fascia and much more. Code Right Technologies developed a software application thats helping them to manage the enquiries and quotations of their customers, making their business more scalable.
- EC Property: EC Property is a Specialised Property Consultancy and Process Management Operation. Code Right Technologies developed a software application to manage property sales instantly. By using our application, EC property can manage their property sales process easily, making their business more scalable.
- RD (JavaScript): Did extensive RD on various technologies and techniques and create documentation for the same to improve the efficiency and security of the software.

#### Projects

• LinedIn clone: Made a linkedin clone to learn the basics of MERN stack as well as firebase.

# Programming Skills

- Languages: Python, Javascript(ES 6+), GOLang( currently learning)
- Technologies: AWS, React, Angular, Node.JS, Express.JS, MongoDB, Docker, PostgreSQL, Jenkins, SALT stack( currently learning)
- Plan to learn: Web3, Neo4j, Microservices, Kubernetes, EKS, RabbitMQ/Kafka